Finding Aid for the Adeline Levine Love Canal Collection, 1893-1995 (bulk 1978-1995)
Buffalo History Museum. Research Library
Adeline Levine Love Canal Collection, 1893-1995
1978 - 1995
Mss. C94-2
Levine, Adeline
54 boxes, 24 audio cassettes, and 4 video cassettes (26 linear feet)
Contains research, reports, papers, and articles, 1978-1990; newspaper clippings, 1978-1999, with index, 1978-1995; photographs and slides, 1978-1989; audio and video cassettes, 1978-1986; personal interviews and field notes, 1978-1987; correspondence and materials relating to environmental activists and organizations, including Lois Gibbs and the Citizen's Clearinghouse for Hazardous Wastes, Inc., 1978-1989, 1995.
The Buffalo History Museum 1 Museum Court Buffalo, NY 14216 Phone: 716-873-9644 ext. 306 Fax: 716-873-8754 Email: library@buffalohistory.org URI: http://www.buffalohistory.org
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
I and II are open by special permission only. Users must present scholarly credentials and sign an authorization form, stating that identities of participants will not be revealed. A copy of the authorization form will be retained by BECHS and Dr. Levine. The materials shall not be reproduced by any means (photographs, photocopies, or electronic scanning). These requirements will remain in force until 2045, or until such time as the Archivist or Dr. Levine see fit.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated by Dr. Levine over the period 1993-1995. The slide show and audio cassette tapes for "Love Canal: The Issues and The Controversies" were donated by the State University of New York at Buffalo, along with video cassette tape no. 3, "Love Canal" (undated).
Acc. no. 93-63.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Biographical and Historical Note
Dr. Adeline Levine was a professor of sociology at the State University of New York at Buffalo from 1968 to 1990. She conducted research on the sociological aspects of the Love Canal controversy from 1978 on. She has written many papers and articles on Love Canal, and in 1982, she published Love Canal: Science, Politics, and People (available in the BECHS library).
The Love Canal is an area of land located in the city of Niagara Falls, New York. In the 1800's William Love attempted, unsuccessfully, to dig a canal linking his lands with the Niagara River. Hooker Chemical and Plastics Corporation gained title to the land, and allegedly used the site as a toxic waste dump. In 1953, Hooker transferred the parcel to the Niagara Falls Board of Education. The land was subsequently zoned residential, and part of the parcel was used to build the 99th Street School. The impact of toxic chemicals on the health of area residents became a topic of controversy, and the site was declared a federal emergency disaster area. Residents, Hooker, and state and federal governmental agencies became embroiled in disputes over scientific studies and proposed courses of action. The area was declared, habitable in July of 1982. A 1994 decision in U.S. v. Hooker denied punitive damages for Love Canal residents. Legislation is still ongoing.
Scope and Content Note
The bulk of the collection consists of materials from 1978-1995, but a few materials on Niagara Falls history, Hooker Chemical Corporation, and the land transfer of the Love Canal, pre-date the 1970's.
The first series of the collection consists of the interviews of Love Canal residents conducted by Levine in 1978 and 1979. The second series contains field notes written by Levine (and others) covering the period August 15, 1978 to 1987. These notes describe events and experiences relating to Love Canal, and contain correspondence, ephemera, and various other materials. These two series are open by special permission only (see below for more information).
The third series contains miscellaneous materials collected by Levine while at Love Canal, including forms and questionnaires distributed to residents; information on liver tests and compound testing; and maps.
IV contains Levine's own research on Love Canal. Materials from a 1978-1979 seminar conducted by Levine at the University at Buffalo, including students' papers, make up the first subseries. Levine's own papers, talks, and published articles, including manuscript drafts and notes, are arranged chronologically. The series also contains materials relating to the writing, publication and publicity of Levine's book, Love Canal: Science, Politics, and People, and her slide presentation, "Love Canal: The Issues and The Controversies". Lastly, copies of materials donated to the University at Buffalo archives are included, and are arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
The fifth series contains information on citizens' groups and grassroots environmental organizations; the Love Canal Homeowners Association, and Lois Gibb's activities at Love Canal; Citizen's Clearinghouse for Hazardous Wastes, Inc., organized by Gibbs; the Ecumenical Task Force; and materials and newsletters from various other groups.
VI contains reports, advertisements, and publications by and about Hooker Chemical and the Chemical Manufacturer's Association. Series VII includes census information for Niagara Falls, information on the history of the area and on William Love, and materials on the Niagara Falls Board of Education. Series VIII contains transcripts of testimony and other materials relating to state and congressional hearings on Love Canal, and copies of lawsuits and complaints filed by various parties.
The ninth series is made up of documents and correspondence produced by governmental agencies; it includes the New York State Department of Health Collected Documents on Love Canal. The tenth series contains reports and research produced by scholars and governmental agencies from 1977-1983, and articles clipped by Levine for her own research. Subseries X.B. includes reports from Beverly Paigen, a cancer research scientist at Roswell Park Memorial Institute, who volunteered her services to the Love Canal homeowners.
Photographs, as well as negatives and slides, taken of the Love Canal area and residents, from 1978-1989 make up Series XI. The twelfth series contains newspaper clippings, 1978-1995. The articles cover all aspects of the Love Canal disaster and persons involved, as well as news on other environmental disasters and toxic pollution. The articles have been taken from Buffalo Evening News, Buffalo Courier-Express, Niagara Gazette, New York Times, Washington Post, St. Louis Post-Dispatch, and a number of other papers. Levine's article index is included, and notations have been made to indicate which articles are contained in the collection.
The last series contains audio cassettes of Levine and others, 1978-1983; and video cassettes, including In Our Own Backyard by Lynn Corcoran.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in thirteen Series:
I. Interviews
II. Field Notes
III. Collected Materials
IV. Levine Research
V. Citizens Groups
VI. Hooker and Chemical Manufacturers Association
VII. Niagara Falls and William Love
VIII. Legal Aspects
IX. Government Documents
X. Research and Reports
XI. Photographs, Negatives, and Slides
XII. Newspaper Clippings
XIII. Audio and Video Cassettes.
Container List
- Interviews, I.
  - Blank forms and questionnaires (Box-folder 1.1)
  - Key (Box-folder 1.2)
  - 101 (Box-folder 1.3)
  - 102 (Box-folder 1.4)
  - 103 (Box-folder 1.5)
  - 104 (Box-folder 1.6)
  - 105 (Box-folder 1.7)
  - 106 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - 107 (Box-folder 1.9)
  - 108 (Box-folder 1.10)
  - 109 (Box-folder 1.11)
  - 110 (Box-folder 1.12)
  - 111 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - 112 (Box-folder 1.14)
  - 113 (Box-folder 1.15)
  - 114 (Box-folder 1.16)
  - 115 (Box-folder 1.17)
  - 116 (Box-folder 1.18)
  - 117 (Box-folder 1.19)
  - 118 (Box-folder 1.20)
  - 119 (Box-folder 1.21)
  - 120 (Box-folder 1.22)
  - 121 (Box-folder 1.23)
  - 122 (Box-folder 1.24)
  - 123 (Box-folder 1.25)
  - 124 (Box-folder 2.1)
  - 125 (Box-folder 2.2)
  - 126 (Box-folder 2.3)
  - 127 (Box-folder 2.4)
  - 128 (Box-folder 2.5)
  - 129 (Box-folder 2.6)
  - 134 (Box-folder 2.7)
  - 135 (Box-folder 2.8)
  - 136 (Box-folder 2.9)
  - 137 (Box-folder 2.10)
  - 138 (Box-folder 2.11)
  - 139 (Box-folder 2.12)
  - 140 (Box-folder 2.13)
  - 141 (Box-folder 2.14)
  - 142 (Box-folder 2.15)
  - 143 (Box-folder 2.16)
  - 144 (Box-folder 2.17)
  - 145, 245 (combined) (Box-folder 2.18)
  - 146, 246 (combined) (Box-folder 3.1)
  - 147 (Box-folder 3.2)
  - 148 (Box-folder 3.3)
  - 149 (Box-folder 3.4)
  - 150, 151 (combined) (Box-folder 3.5)
  - 152, 153 (combined) (Box-folder 3.6)
  - 154 (Box-folder 3.7)
  - 155 (Box-folder 3.8)
  - 356, 256 (combined) (Box-folder 3.9)
  - 157, 158 (combined) (Box-folder 3.10)
  - 159, 259 (combined) (Box-folder 3.11)
  - 160 (Box-folder 3.12)
  - 161 (Box-folder 3.13)
  - 162 (Box-folder 3.14)
  - 202 (Box-folder 4.1)
  - 204 (Box-folder 4.2)
  - 206 (Box-folder 4.3)
  - 207 (Box-folder 4.4)
  - 213 (Box-folder 4.5)
  - 214 (Box-folder 4.6)
  - 215 (Box-folder 4.7)
  - 216 (Box-folder 4.8)
  - 217 (Box-folder 4.9)
  - 218 (Box-folder 4.10)
  - 219 (Box-folder 4.11)
  - 221 (Box-folder 4.12)
  - 222 (Box-folder 4.13)
  - 224 (Box-folder 4.14)
  - 225 (Box-folder 4.15)
  - 226 (Box-folder 4.16)
  - 227 (Box-folder 4.17)
  - 229 (Box-folder 4.18)
  - 234 (Box-folder 4.19)
  - 235 (Box-folder 5.1)
  - 236 (Box-folder 5.2)
  - 237 (Box-folder 5.3)
  - 238 (Box-folder 5.4)
  - 240 (Box-folder 5.5)
  - 241 (Box-folder 5.6)
  - 242 (Box-folder 5.7)
  - 245 (Box-folder 5.8)
  - 247 (Box-folder 5.9)
  - 248 (Box-folder 5.10)
  - 249 (Box-folder 5.11)
  - 251 (Box-folder 5.12)
  - 252, 253 (combined) (Box-folder 5.13)
  - 255 (Box-folder 5.14)
  - 257 (Box-folder 5.15)
  - 260 (Box-folder 5.16)
  - 261 (Box-folder 5.17)
  - 262 (Box-folder 5.18)
- Field Notes, II.
  - August 15-August 25, 1978 (Box-folder 6.1)
  - September 8-September 14, 1978 (Box-folder 6.2)
  - September 15-September 28, 1978 (Box-folder 6.3)
  - September 29-October 5, 1978 (Box-folder 6.4)
  - October 6-October 18, 1978 (Box-folder 6.5)
  - October 19-November 1, 1978 (Box-folder 6.6)
  - November 2-November 30, 1978 (Box-folder 6.7)
  - December 1-December 15, 1978 (Box-folder 6.8)
  - December 16-December 31, 1978 (Box-folder 6.9)
  - January 1-31, 1979 (Box-folder 6.10)
  - February 1979 (Box-folder 7.1)
  - March 1979 (Box-folder 7.2)
  - April 1979 (Box-folder 7.3)
  - May 1979 (Box-folder 7.4)
  - May 17, 1979 - LCHA by-laws (Box-folder 7.5)
  - June-July 1979 (Box-folder 7.6)
  - August-September 1979 (Box-folder 7.7)
  - October-December 1979 (Box-folder 7.8)
  - Gibbs chronology, April 1978-November 1979 (Box-folder 7.9)
  - January-April 1980 (Box-folder 7.10)
  - May 1980 (Box-folder 7.11)
  - Gibbs chronology, February-May 1980 (Box-folder 8.1)
  - June-August 1980 (Box-folder 8.2)
  - September-October 1980 (Box-folder 8.3)
  - November-December 1980 (Box-folder 8.4)
  - Press releases 1980 (Box-folder 8.5)
  - Thomas Report October 1980-January 1981 (Box-folder 8.6)
  - January-February 1981 (Box-folder 8.7)
  - March-December 1981 (Box-folder 8.8)
  - 1982 (Box-folder 8.9)
    (includes chronology, 1940's-1979)
  - 1983 (Box-folder 8.10)
  - Field notes. 1984-1987 (bulk 1984-1985) (Box-folder 8.11)
- Collected Materials, III.
  - Field notes. Miscellaneous (includes newspaper article indices, August 1978) (Box-folder 8.12)
  - Love Canal Information Form, Allen, Lippes, and Shonn (Box-folder 8.13)
  - Property and health questionnaire, LCHA (Box-folder 8.14)
  - Gannett survey questionnaires (Box-folder 9.1)
  - Revitalization contracts and loan agreements (Box-folder 9.2)
  - Information on compounds tested at Love Canal (Box-folder 9.3)
  - Information on liver nests (Box-folder 9.4)
  - Maps (Box-folder 9.5)
  - Initial proposal and funding for Love Canal Study, August 1978 (Box-folder 9.6)
  - Expenditures, 1978 (Box-folder 9.7)
  - Funding (Box-folder 9.8)
  - Funding. Moir Tanner Award, January 1979 (Box-folder 9.9)
  - Funding. Beinecke Application, January 1979 (Box-folder 9.10)
- Levine Research, IV.
  Arranged in six series:
  IV.A. Seminar
  IV.B. Research Methods
  IV.C. Papers, Talks, Articles
  IV.D. Various
  IV.E. Book Materials
  IV.F. SUNYAB Materials.
  - Seminar, IV.A.
    - 1978-1979. Course description and information on class members (Box-folder 9.11)
    - Meeting agendas (Box-folder 9.12)
    - Papers. Hufsmith. "The Corporate Response of Hooker to the Love Canal Situation" December 1978 (Box-folder 9.13)
    - Papers. Presented at 49th Annual Meeting of the Eastern Sociological Society, March 16, 1979., Levine. "The Love Canal - A Man-Made Environmental Disaster." Levine, et al. "The Love Canal: A Sociologist's Perspective." (Box-folder 9.14)
    - Papers. Presented at "Love Canal: Lessons for Society, University at Buffalo, March 21, 1979. Summarized by Levine. "Health and Social Effects." (Box-folder 9.15)
    - Papers. Presented at 50th Annual Meeting of the Eastern Psychological Association, April 19, 1979., Barker. "Stress and Coping at Love Canal." Cornwell. "Interorganizational Relationships in a Disaster Setting: An Adversarial Model." Hufsmith. "The Response of Love Canal Residents to Their Community and Government." Levine. "The Love Canal: Setting, History, and Methods of Study." Ploughman. "Mass Media in Disaster: Love Canal Coverage." Rowe. "Victim Life Stage Perceptions of Environmental Crisis." (Box-folder 9.16)
    - Papers. Presented at the 10th annual Conference of the Environmental Design Research Association, June 9, 1979., Hufsmith. "The Problems of Hazardous Waste Disposal: In Search of a New Equilibrium." Rowe. "The Familial Impact of the Love Canal. Section I: Life Stage Perceptions." (Box-folder 9.17)
    - Papers. Presented at 32rd Annual Meeting of the Gerontological Society, November 29, 1979., Rowe. "Life Stage Responses to Environmental Disaster." (Box-folder 10.1)
    - Papers. Masters project proposal. Brennan. "The Emergence and Persistence of Citizens Groups at the Love Canal." 1980-1981. (Box-folder 10.2)
    - Newsletter, Environmental Sociology Section of American Sociological Association, Winter 1979. (Box-folder 10.3)
    - Correspondence, October 1978-September 1979 (Box-folder 10.4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 10.5)
  - Research Methods, IV.B.
    - Materials for J. Feather's class on evaluation, January 1981 (Box-folder 10.10.7)
    - Bulletin board materials (includes address lists, articles, announcements, correspondence) (Box-folder 10.8)
    - Requests for papers (Box-folder 10.9)
    - Public Health Conference, NYS Public Health Association, Buffalo, June 8-11, 1980 (Box-folder 10.10)
    - Readings and creative conversation (Box-folder 10.11)
    - Articles (Box-folder 10.12)
    - Bertell on DOE study, January 1979 (Box-folder 10.13)
    - Shackman. "Accuracy of interview self-reports in estimating prevalence of health problems." (Box-folder 10.14)
    - Speech at Fredonia, March 26, 1979 (Box-folder 11.1)
    - Speech at Beaver College, May 2, 1979 (Box-folder 11.2)
  - Levine Papers, Talks, Articles, IV.C.
    Arranged in three sections: Papers, Talks, and Articles.
    - Papers
      - "The Philosophical Contribution of Thomas Huxley" November 30, 1961 (Box-folder 11.3)
      - "Scientific Decision Making in a Politicized Setting" August 24-27, 1979, SSSP. (Box-folder 11.4)
      - "Science and Politics at Love Canal: The Use of Scientists, the Non-Use of Science" March 1981, Nazareth College. (Box-folder 11.5)
      - "The Psycho/Social Impact of Toxic Chemical Waste Dumps" October 27-28, 1981, NIEHS. (Box-folder 11.6)
      - "Key Findings and Methodological Issues in the Study of Communities Exposed to Toxic Pollution" April 18, 1982, EDRA. (Box-folder 11.7)
      - "The Citizens Organization as a Countervailing Force," and "The Psycho/Social Impact of the Toxic Chemical Waste Dump at the Love Canal" October 24-27, 1982. Conference on social Impact Assessment., [3 folders]; Includes other papers and reports from conference: Edelstein: "Social Impacts of A1 Turi Landfill, Inc."; Third Annual Report. Technical Advisory Committee on the Nuclear Fuel Waste Management Program, June 1982; Krawetz. "Hazardous Waste Management: A Review of Social Concerns and Aspects of Public Involvement." (Dept. of Environment, Alberta) (Box-folder 11.8)
      - Conference on Social Impact Assessment, continued. Conference materials. (Box-folder 11.9)
      - Conference on Social Impact Assessment, continued. Correspondence. (Box-folder 12.l)
      - "Love Canal: Scientific Controversy and Policy Dilemma" April 19, 1983, University of Cincinnati. (Box-folder 12.2)
      - "Scientific Decisions and Public Policy: Love Canal" April 22, 1983, SUNY/McHaster. Also includes paper by Nossal. "Environmental Management and Canadian-American Relations: The Role Of the International Joint Commission." (Box-folder 12.3)
      - "Who Does What to Whom? The Media and Science at Love Canal" September 2, 1983, ASS. (Box-folder 12.4)
      - "Statement for the Committee on Public Awareness, Illinois Hazardous Waste Task Force" October 19, 1983 (Box-folder 12.5-12.6)
      - "Trust Me Trust He! Chromosomes and Credibility at Love Canal" April 12, 1984, AAPA (Box-folder 12.7)
      - "A Comment on 'A study of cytogenetic patterns in persons living near the Love Canal'" June 20, 1984. (Box-folder 12.8)
      - "Love Canal: Ethical and Methodological Problems in Field Research" August 26, 1984, SSSP. (Box-folder 12.9)
      - Levine and Stone. "Reactions to Collective Stress: Correlates of Active Citizen Participation at Love Canal" August 1984, APA. (Box-folder 12.10)
      - Levine and Stone. "Residents' Perceptions of the Hazard of Love Canal: Problems and Changes to Self and Family" August 1984, APA. (Box-folder 12.11)
      - Levine and Stone. "The Question of the Habitability of Love Canal: The Role of Scientific Expertise and Technical Data in Establishing Criteria (Making New Science with Immediate Policy Implications)" March 19, 1988, SUNY. (Box-folder 12.12)
      - "Love Canal, 1989: Still Seeking a Solution" May 19, 1989, Johns Hopkins. (Box-folder 12.13)
    - Levine Talks
      - "The Love Canal: Living on a Toxic Waste Dump Site" May 10, 1979, Rochester Industrial Engineers Society. (Box-folder 12.14)
      - "Science and Politics at Love Canal" January 22, 1981, UC Berkeley. February 27, 1981, Siena College. (Box-folder 12.15)
      - "The Love Canal: Controversies and Dilemmas" January 11, 1982, UC Davis. January 13 1983, UC Berkeley. (Box-folder 13.1)
      - "Psycho/Social Impact" March 10, March 12 and April 2, 1982. (Box-folder 13.2)
      - "Key Findings and Methodological Issues in the Study of Communities Exposed to Toxic Pollution" April and August, 1982. (Box-folder 13.3)
      - "The Love Canal: Controversies and Costs" December 3, 1982, SUNY. (Box-folder 13.4)
      - "Love Canal Before and After: Dilemmas and Controversies" March 15, 1983, Cornell. (Box-folder 13.5)
      - "Scientific Decisions and Public Policy" April 27, 1983, SUNY. (Box-folder 13.6)
      - "Scientific Controversy and Policy Dilemma" May 12, 1983, Buffalo Area Studies Group. (Box-folder 13.7)
      - "Love Canal: Science, Politics, And People" August 2, 1983," SUNY. (Box-folder 13.8)
      - ASA talk, 1983. (Box-folder 13.9)
      - "Who Does What to Whom? The Media and Science at Love Canal" January 5, 1984, UC San Francisco. (Box-folder 13.10)
      - Notes and materials from speaking engagements, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 13.11)
      - Notes and materials from speaking engagements, 1983-1984, undated (Box-folder 13.12)
    - Levine Articles
      - Articles published by Levine, 1970-1989:, Levine and Levine. "The Social Context of Evaluative Research: A Case Study." Evaluation Quarterly 1(4), November 1977, 515-542. Levine and Levine. "Editorial Opinion: Science and Politics: a Dangerous Mix." Journal of Community Psychology 8 ( 1980), 189-90. Reprinted from Buffalo Evening News, December 23, 1979. "The Psycho/Social Impact of Toxic Waste Dumps." Congressional Record, Extensions of Remarks, December 16, 1981, E5894-5896. Book review of Reflections on Science and the Media, by June Greenfield. Contemporary Sociology 14(3), May 1985, 368-369. Levine and Stone. "Reactions to Collective Stress: Correlates of Active Citizen Participation at Love Canal." Beyond the Individual: Environmental Approaches and Prevention, Prevention in Human Services 4(½), Fall 1985/Winter 1986, 153-177. "Love Canal: Ethical and Methodological Problems in Field Work." International Journal of Mass Emergencies and Disasters 4(1), March 1986, 79-84. "Love Canal and the Limits of Scientific Proof." Natural Resources and Environment 2(2), Fall 1986, 21-23, 59-61. "Love Canal: An Update." Impact Assessment Today, Volume II. Edited by Becker and Porter. Interventions in the Welfare State, Part I. Utrecht: Uitgeverij Jan can Arkel, 1986, 817-824. Levine and Stone. "Threats to People and What They Value: Residents' Perceptions of the Hazards of Love Canal." Advances in Environmental Psychology Vol. 6: Exposure to Hazardous Substances: Psychological Parameters. Edited by Lebovits, Baum, and Singer. Hillsdale, NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, 1986, 109-130. "Psychological Impact of Toxic Chemical Waste Dumps." Environmental Health Perspectives 78 (1988), 15-17. Levine and Stone. "The Question of Habitability of Love Canal: The Role of Scientific Expertise and Technical Data in Establishing Criteria (Making New Science with Immediate Policy Implications).": A Critical Appraisal Environmental Dispute Resolution in the Great Lakes Region. Edited by Bankert and Flint. Great Lakes Monograph No. 1. Great Lakes Program, SUNY, Buffalo, NY, November 1988, 132-146. "Communications and Preparedness for Chemical Accidents." Methods for Assessing and Reducing Injury from Chemical Accidents. Edited by Bourdeau and Green. SCOPE, Published by John Wiley and Sons, Ltd., 1989. (Box-folder 13.13)
    - Levine notes for extended interviews (Box-folder 13.14)
  - Various, VI.D.
    - Slide show scripts and identification cards (Box-folder 14.1)
    - Notebooks. September 1978-February 1979; February-May 1979; May 1979-October 1980; and August 18, 1988 (Box-folder 14.2)
    - Correspondence, 1979-1990 (Box-folder 14.3)
  - Book Materials, VI.E.
    - Outline (Box-folder 14.4)
    - Correspondence with Lexington Books, January 1980-December 1981 (Box-folder 14.5)
    - Correspondence with Lexington Books, 1982 (Box-folder 14.6)
    - Correspondence with Lexington Books, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 14.7)
    - Correspondence with other publishers, May 1979-June 1980 (Box-folder 14.8)
    - Publicity. Endorsements, December 1981, November-December 1982 (Box-folder 15.1)
    - Publicity. Close, Goldsen, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 15.2)
    - Publicity. Other than publisher, December 1981-March 1982 (Box-folder 15.3)
    - Publicity. Other than publisher, April-August 1982 (Box-folder 15.4)
    - Publicity. Other than publisher, September 1982-Summer 1983 (Box-folder 15.5)
    - Slide show ("Love Canal: The Issues and Controversies"). Publicity. 1983 (Box-folder 15.6)
    - Slide show. Publicity. 1984-1986 (Box-folder 15.7)
  - SUNYAB Archives, VI.F
    - Correspondence with UB Archives, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 16.1)
    - Copies of documents donated to UB, by correspondent, A-K (Box-folder 16.2)
    - Copies of documents donated to UB, L-N (Box-folder 16.3)
    - Copies of documents donated to UB, P-W (Box-folder 16.4)
- Citizens Groups, V.
  Arranged in three series:
  V.A. Love Canal Homeowners Association
  V.B. Citizen's Clearinghouse for Hazardous Wastes, Inc.
  V.C. Various
  - Love Canal Homeowners Association, V.A.
    - Love Canal Homeowners Association (LCHA) materials (Box-folder 16.5)